AMANDA INNIS UX/UI DESIGNER

PORTFOLIO: amandainnis.github.io CONTACT: amanda.innis@gmail.com

EDUCATION

2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY: UXDI

User Experience Design Immersive, New York, NY (Sept-Nov)

2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Design Circuits
New York, NY (July-Dec)

MFA 2014

RUTGERS UNIVERSITY

Master of Fine Arts in Painting

Graduate Teaching Fellowship

BFA-AE 2006

SCHOOL of the ART INSTITUTE of CHICAGO BFA-AE, Bachelor of Fine Arts with a Certification in Art Education

BHA 2003

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY
Bachelor of Humanities and Arts (BHA)

DESIGN



Sketch 3



Photoshop

Illustrator



Omnigraffle

PROTOTYPE



InVision



Principle



(3),(5)

Hype 3

POP

CODE



HTML 5



GitHub



SublimeText

SUMMARY

I am a UX/UI designer, artist and coder in HTML and CSS. I love what I do. I'm an artist so I look at my craft with enjoyment, discipline and hunger to learn more and build more. If I'm not working on designing, building or user-testing a responsive website, I'm in Illustrator working on graphics or on Codeacademy learning JavaScript.

My career has evolved over the past ten years from teaching and art-making to digital design. Teaching is what lead me to this field: thinking from another person's perspective and designing an experience for them. Art-making has given me a keen eye for palette, layout, typography, graphics and an ability to implement these in CSS. Check out my portfolio (top right) and give me an opportunity to show you what I can do.

SKILLS

Research, comparative analysis, synthesis, wireframing, prototyping, user testing, presenting, hifi mock-ups, digital design, visual design, icon design, responsive web design, coding in HTML and CSS.

EXPERIENCE

UI / UX DESIGNER + CODER, LUNCHBOX

New York, NY (Feb + March, 2016)

This independent project with Marco Pariente-Cohen is intended to replace the USDA's paper application for free lunches for public school students. The paper application has confused users and prevented many qualified applicants from getting access to this program. We redesigned the sequence and presentation of information and created an online application to minimize confusion and enable more users to complete it successfully. *My role: Research, design, illustration, wireframes and coding in HTML and CSS.*

Marco's role: JS, Ruby and back-end development.

VISUAL / WEB DESIGN CONSULTANT, PLUM ALLEY INVESTMENTS

New York, NY (Contract work for Dec + Jan, 2015-2016)

My role included email design and coding, graphic design as well as creating taglines and visuals for the upcoming website. The homepage for the new website had to communicate the message that investing in private companies could change the world, while also adhering to preexisting brand criteria. My tagline "Shape the world by investing..." and design met both criteria and exceeded expectations.

UX / UI DESIGNER, CHARLIE

New York, NY (Nov 2015)

I redesigned the homepage for a marketing company which connected their message and their purpose. The design challenge began with user-testing the existing homepage and doing comparative analysis on similar marketing companies. I created a design-map out of research findings and developed a design that appealed to user emotions (ie. the need to see a human face in order to dispel their pre-existing idea that the marketing company was a robot). Team members included Amelia Ruslim and Kevin Widener

ADJUNCT DRAWING INSTRUCTOR, RIDER UNIVERSITY

Lawrenceville, NJ (May-June, 2015)

Taught a 3 week intensive on fundamentals.

ADJUNCT DRAWING INSTRUCTOR, <u>RUTGERS UNIVERSITY</u>

New Brunswick, NJ (Sept 2012- Dec 2014)

Taught 5 semesters of drawing fundamentals.

ELEMENTARY ART TEACHER, CHICAGO PUBLIC SCHOOLS

Chicago, IL (Aug 2008 - June 2010)